In this video, I'll be showing you how to load image data.
在这一段视频中 我将演示如何加载图像数据
This is really useful for what you'll be doing in real projects.
这对实际项目非常有用
So previously, we used MNIST.
我们之前用过 MNIST
Fashion-MNIST were just toy datasets for testing your networks,
Fashion-MNIST 是用于测试网络的样本数据集
but you'll be using full-size images like you'd get from smartphone cameras and
但现在要用的是全尺寸图像 它们可能是智能手机的照相机拍摄的 也可能
your actual projects that you'll be doing with deep learning networks.
来自深度学习网络创建的实际项目
So with this, we'll be using a dataset of cat and dog photos, super cute.
我们将使用猫狗照片的数据集 它们非常可爱
That come from Kaggle. So, if you want to learn more about it,
这个数据集来自 Kaggle 要了解更多信息
you can just click on this link.
可以点击这个链接
So, you can see our images are now much larger,
可以看出 与 MNIST 和 fashion-MNIST 中的图像相比
much higher resolution and they're coming in
这些图像尺寸大得多 分辨率大得多
different shapes and sizes than what we saw with MNIST and fashion-MNIST.
具有不同形状和尺寸
So, the first step to using these is to actually load them in with PyTorch.
第一步就是用 PyTorch 加载这些图像
Then once you have them in,
加载之后
you can train a network using these things.
可以用它们训练网络
So, the easiest way to load in our image data is with datasets.ImageFolder.
加载图像数据的最简单方法是 datasets.ImageFolder
This is from torchvision, that datasets module.
这个数据集模块来自 torchvision
So basically, you just pass in a path to your dataset,
可以将数据集的路径
so into the folder where your data is
传入到数据所在的
sitting into image folder and give us some transforms,
图像文件夹 执行 transforms
which we talked about before.
我们之前讲过 transforms
I'll go into some more detail about transforms next.
接下来我将详细讲解
So, the image folder,
图像文件夹中的
it expects your files and directories to look like this,
文件和目录应这样创建
where you have some root directory that's where all your data.
所有数据都应存在根目录中
Then each of the different classes has their own folder.
每个不同的类应有单独的文件夹
So in this case, we have two classes.
现在有两个类
We have dog and cat.
狗和猫
So, we have these two folders, dog and cat.
所以有两个文件夹 狗和猫
Get more classes like for MNIST,
MNIST 中的类更多
now you have ten classes.
有十个类
There will be one folder for each of the different digits, right?
每个不同数字都会有一个文件夹 对吧？
Those are our classes or labels.
这些就是类或标签
Then within each of the specific class folders,
在每个特定类文件夹内
you have your images that belong to those classes.
图像都属于这个类
So, in your dog folder are going to be all of
所以 狗文件夹里都是狗的图像
your dog pictures and the cat folder are going to be all of your cat pictures.
猫文件夹里都是猫的图像
So, if you're working in a workspace,
如果在 workspace 内操作
then the data should already be there,
数据应该已经存在
but if you're working on your local computer,
但是如果在本地计算机上操作
you can get the data by clicking here.
可以点击这里获取数据
I've also already split this into a training set and test set for you.
我已经把它分成一个训练集和一个测试集
When you load in the image folder,
在图像文件夹中加载时
you need to define some transforms.
需要定义 transforms
So, what I mean by this is you'll want to resize it, you can crop it,
也就是可以缩放 剪裁
you can do a lot of things like typically you'll want to convert it to
也可以转换成
a PyTorch tensor and it is loaded in as a pillow image.
PyTorch 张量 以 PiIlow 图像的形式加载
So, you need to change the image into a tensor.
所以 需要将图片转换成张量
Then you combine these transforms into
然后使用 transforms.compose 将这些
a pipeline of transforms, using transforms.compose.
transforms 合并成 transforms 管道
So, if you want to resize your image to be 255 by 255,
如果想把图像缩放成 255*255
then you say transforms.resize 255 and then you take just the center portion,
写入 transforms.resize 255 只取中间部分
you just crop that out with a size of 224 by 224.
裁剪成 224*224
Then you can convert it to a tensor.
然后将其转换成张量
So, these are the transforms that you'll use and you pass this into
这些 transforms 你都会用到 将其传入 ImageFolder
ImageFolder to define the transforms that you're performing on your images.
定义用于图像的 transforms
Once you have your dataset from your image folder,
图像文件夹中有数据集之后
defining your transforms and then you pass that to dataloader.
定义 transforms 并将其传入数据加载器
From here, you can define your batch size,
可以在这里定义批量大小
so it's the number of images you get per batch like per loop through
也就是每批的图像数量 一批就是这个数据加载器中的一个循环
this dataloader and then you can also do things like set shuffle to true.
然后可以将混排设为“真”
So basically, what shuffle does is it
混排就是
randomly shuffles your data every time you start a new epoch.
每次开始新周期时随机排列数据
This is useful because when you're training your network,
这个非常有用 因为在训练网络时
we prefer it the second time it goes through to see your images in a different order,
我们希望网络第二次看见的图像呈现不同顺序
the third time it goes through you see your images in a different order.
第三次看见的图像又呈现另一种顺序
Rather than just learning in the same order every time because then this could
而不是每次都按相同顺序进行学习 因为
introduce weird artifacts in how your network is learning from your data.
网络对数据进行学习时 会出现伪迹
So, the thing to remember is that
请记住
this dataloader that you get from this class dataloader,
从这个类数据加载器中获取的数据加载器
the actual dataloader object itself, is a generator.
实际的数据加载器对象本身是一个生成器
So, this means to get data out of it you actually have to loop through it
如需从中获得数据 必须对其进行循环
like in a for loop or you need to call iter on it,
例如 for 循环 或者调用 iter
to turn into an iterator.
转换成迭代器
Then call next to get the data out of it.
然后调用 next 从中获取数据
Really what's happening here in this for loop,
这个 for 循环
this for images comma labels in dataloader is actually turning this into an iterator.
for images, labels in dataloader 实际上将其转换成迭代器
Every time you go through a loop, it calls next.
每次进行循环时 就会调用 next
So basically, this for loop is an automatic way of doing this.
所以 这个 for 循环是自动进行的
Okay. So, I'm going to leave up to you is to define some transforms,
好了 现在请你定义 transforms
create your image folder and then pass that image folder to create a dataloader.
创建并传入图像件夹 然后创建数据加载器
Then if you do everything right,
完成之后
you should see an image that looks like this.
会看到这样的图像
So, that's the basic way of loading in your data.
这就是加载数据的方法
You can also do what's called data augmentation.
也可以进行数据扩张
So, what this is is you want to introduce randomness into your data itself.
它是给数据本身赋予随机性
What this can do is you can imagine if you have images,
如果有一组图像
you can translate where a cat shows up and you can rotate the cat,
可以变动猫图像的显示位置 旋转猫图像
you can scale the cat,
缩放猫图像
you can crop different parts of things,
剪裁不同部位
you can mirror it horizontally and vertically.
也可以进行横向或竖向镜像调整
What this does is it helps your network generalized
这有助于网络进行泛化
because it's seen these images in different scales,
因为它看到的图像呈现不同比例
at different orientations and so on.
不同方向等
This really helps your network train and will
这有助于训练网络
eventually lead to better accuracy on your validation tests.
最终在验证测试中获得更高的准确度
Here, I'll let you define some transforms for training data.
现在请你对训练数据定义 transforms
So here, you want to do the data augmentation thing,
可以进行数据扩张
where you're randomly cropping and resizing and rotating
随机剪裁 缩放和旋转图像
your images and also define transforms for the test dataset.
为测试数据集定义 transforms
So, one thing to remember is that for testing when you're doing your validation,
请记住 在测试期间进行验证时
you don't want to do any of this data augmentation.
不需要进行任何数据扩张
So basically, you just want to just do a resize and center crop of your images.
只需要缩放和剪裁图像
This is because you want your validation to be similar
这是因为 我们希望验证结果
to the eventual like in state of your model.
接近模型的最终状态
Once you train your data,
训练数据时
you're going to be sending in pictures of cats and dogs.
要发送猫狗的图像
So, you want your validation set to look pretty much
我们希望验证集非常接近
exactly like what your eventual input images will look like.
最终输入的图像
If you do all that correctly,
如果操作正确
you should see training examples are like this.
会看到这样的训练样本
So, you can see how these are rotated.
可以看出它们有没有旋转
Then you're testing examples should look like this,
测试样本是这样的
where they are scaled proportionally and they're not rotated.
按比例缩放 没有旋转
Once you've loaded this data,
加载数据之后
you should try to build a network based on what you've already
应尝试按照所学知识建立网络
learned that can then classify cats and dogs from this dataset.
使其能够对这个数据集中的猫和狗进行分类
I should warn you this is actually a pretty tough challenge and it probably won't work.
提醒你一下 这实际是一个非常难的挑战 很可能不会成功
So, don't try too hard at it.
所以 不必过于辛苦尝试
Before you used MNIST and fashion-IMNIST.
你之前使用了 MNIST 和 fashion-IMNIST
Those are very simple images, right?
图像都非常简单 对吧？
So, there are 20 by 28.
大小是 20*28
They only have grayscale colors.
而是都是灰度图像
But now these cat and dog images, they're much larger.
但是现在这些猫狗图像大得多
Their colors, so you have those three channels.
颜色复杂 所以有三个颜色通道
Just in general, it's going to be very difficult to build
总体而言 建立一个能够通过全连接网络
a classifier that can do this just using this fully connected network.
实现这一点的分类器 会非常难
The next part, I'll show you how to use a pre-trained network to build a model that
在下一部分 我将演示如何使用预训练网络构建模型
can actually classify these cat and dog images. Cheers.
从而对这些猫狗图像进行分类 谢谢